Create Account or Log In:

Creating an account or logging in via facebook/email will let you save your application, and allow you to access your pets medical records and other important information after you adopt or foster.

* * *

Sign In

* * *

* * *

No Thanks

### Sign in

\* Email

\* Password

Remember me

### No Account yet?

    * [
        
        Pet Search
        ==========
        
        Available pets for adoption near you](https://www.wagtopia.com/petsearch)
    * [
        
        Wagtopia MD
        ===========
        
        Online Vet chat appointments 24/7](https://www.wagtopia.com/wagtopiamd)
    * [
        
        Microchip Search
        ================
        
        Search pet's microchip](https://petlover.petstablished.com/microchip_search)
    * [
        
        Register Microchip
        ==================
        
        Register your pet's microchip](https://petlover.petstablished.com/microchip_registry_public/confirm_microchip_number)
    * [
        
        Register Smart Tag
        ==================
        
        Protect your pet the smart way](https://petlover.petstablished.com/smart_tag_registrations.confirm_smart_tag_code)
    * [
        
        Purchase Microchips
        ===================
        
        Place a new microchip order](https://petlover.petstablished.com/microchip_order_public)
    * [
        
        Smart Tag Search
        ================
        
        Search your pet's smart tag](https://petlover.petstablished.com/smart_tag_search)
    * [
        
        Community
        =========
        
        Find answers to your burning pet health, training ...](https://www.wagtopia.com/blogs)

    * [
        
        Pet Search
        ==========
        
        Available pets for adoption near you](https://www.wagtopia.com/petsearch)
    * [
        
        Wagtopia MD
        ===========
        
        Online Vet chat appointments 24/7](https://www.wagtopia.com/wagtopiamd)
    * [
        
        Microchip Search
        ================
        
        Search pet's microchip](https://petlover.petstablished.com/microchip_search)
    * [
        
        Register Microchip
        ==================
        
        Register your pet's microchip](https://petlover.petstablished.com/microchip_registry_public/confirm_microchip_number)
    * [
        
        Register Smart Tag
        ==================
        
        Protect your pet the smart way](https://petlover.petstablished.com/smart_tag_registrations.confirm_smart_tag_code)
    * [
        
        Purchase Microchips
        ===================
        
        Place a new microchip order](https://petlover.petstablished.com/microchip_order_public)
    * [
        
        Smart Tag Search
        ================
        
        Search your pet's smart tag](https://petlover.petstablished.com/smart_tag_search)
    * [
        
        Community
        =========
        
        Find answers to your burning pet health, training ...](https://www.wagtopia.com/blogs)

Privacy Policy
==============

Petstablished

Last Updated: March 23, 2023

**Privacy Policy**

Welcome to PerfectPetMatch.com LLC (doing business as Wagtopia) (“Wagtopia”)!  Wagtopia understands that privacy and data security are vital concerns to everyone. We respect your privacy and recognize the importance of the information you provide to us. We are committed to protecting your information through our compliance with this Privacy Policy.

When you visit our website (www.wagtopia.com) (the “Site”), create an Account or register with us, or place an order through the Perfectpet Marketplace, we may collect certain information from you. This Privacy Policy describes the types of information we collect when you visit the Site or use the Petstablished services (collectively, our "Services") and our practices for using, maintaining, protecting and disclosing that information.

Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. By accessing or using the Services, you are accepting the policies and practices described in this Privacy Policy. Each time you visit or use the Services, you agree and expressly consent to our collection, use and disclosure of the information that you provide as described in this Policy. Any capitalized terms not defined herein shall have the meaning as set forth in the Terms of Use.  This Privacy Policy may change from time to time (see Changes to Our Privacy Policy below). Your continued use of our Services after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check this Privacy Policy periodically for updates. 

Please note that this Policy does not apply to your use of third-party sites, services, or applications you may access through the Services. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of those third parties for more information regarding their privacy practices.

**What Information Do We Collect?**

We collect several types of information from and about users of our Site and Services. We gather information in the following ways: voluntary registration, voluntary submissions, cookie technology, and location data. 

**Information You Provide to Us.**

* **1\.     Registration**. When you register to use our Services, we collect information that helps us identify you and helps us to administer your account. The more information you provide, the better we can customize our services and your experience to suit your needs and preferences. We collect information you provide directly to us when using the Services. For example, we collect information when you sign up for an Account, complete a form, place an order, participate in any interactive features of the Services, request customer support, or otherwise communicate with us. The types of information we may collect include your name, email address, mailing and billing address and payment information, and any other information you choose to provide.  For purposes of registering and using the Services, we collect certain information that can identify you, such as your name and contact information (email, address and phone number)  (“Personal Information”) We will never sell, rent, or trade Personal Information and will only use it, as needed, to provide the Services and/or fulfill the orders requested by you. If you choose not to provide information that is necessary to provide the Services, you may not be able to use certain aspects or all of the Services.  Wagtopia discloses Personal Information only to those of its employees, contractors, purchasers, sellers, and/or affiliated organizations that (i) need to know the information in order to process it on yours and our behalf, and (ii) that have agreed in writing to non-disclosure restrictions at least as strong as those herein.  Depending on the nature of your inquiry or activities on the Services, we may also ask for other information relevant to your use of the Services.
    * **Microchip registration**. In addition to the above, if you sign up or register your pet in our microchip database, you understand and agree that personal information you provide will be held in a database created and operated by us. You can always choose not to provide certain information, but we do require an email address to be able to register. We only return certain contact and other relevant information about you and your pet. By signing up and including your information on the microchip registry, you agree and understand that people who enter the microchip number will be able to view the contact information you provide (even if those people enter the wrong microchip number that happens to be yours). You are responsible for only including information you are comfortable with others being able to access, and we will not be in any way responsible or liable for persons receiving your information that you provided through the microchip registry.
* **2\.     User Contributions**. The Site may contain video postings, message boards, chat rooms, personal web pages or profiles, forums, bulletin boards, and other interactive features that allow you to post, submit, publish, display, or transmit to other users content or materials on or through the Site (collectively, “User Contributions”). All information you provide may become public on the Site, including any partner or affiliate pages. Your User Contributions are posted on and transmitted to others at your own risk. Although we take reasonable steps to protect your personal information, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. Additionally, we cannot control the actions of other users of the Services with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that your User Contributions will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. 
* **3\.     Payment**. The Company uses Stripe as its third-party payment processor to process credit cards and electronic payments securely for its users. Accordingly, the Company will not store payment information in its system. The processing of payments or credits, as applicable, in connection with your use of the Services will be subject to the terms, conditions, and privacy policies of Stripe and your credit card issuer in addition to those terms specified herein. The Company is not responsible for any errors by Stripe. 

**Information We Collect Automatically.**

As you navigate through and interact with our Services, we may use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions and usage patterns, including:

* **1\.      Cookies**. We use cookies to store and track your preferences to provide you with a more personalized experience. A cookie is a message sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. You can set your browser preferences to reject all cookies, but this will prevent you from using most customized services, and you may have to repeatedly enter personal information in order to participate in various services or promotions. Cookies make your experience easier by saving your preferences and passwords. We also use cookies that contain no personal information at all. These cookies help us estimate our audience size and determine which areas of the Website are the most popular. For more information about how cookies may affect your privacy, please visit [http://allaboutcookies.org/privacy-concerns/](http://allaboutcookies.org/privacy-concerns/). 
* **2\.      IP Address**. We may log information about your computer and internet connection, including your IP address, operating system and browser type, for the purposes of systems administration, or to report information in aggregate form third parties such as advertisers (for example, to identify how many visitors logged in to our Website). We do not provide such third parties with personally identifiable information. 
* **3\.      Usage Details**. We may log details of your visits to our Site and use of our Services, including the resources that you access and use. 
* **4\.      Advertisements**. We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Site. These companies may collect aggregated information about your visit to the Site in order to provide advertisements of interest to you.  
    We also may use these technologies to collect information about your online activities over time and across third-party websites or other online services (behavioral tracking). See below for information on how you can opt out of behavioral tracking on this website and how we respond to web browser signals and other mechanisms that enable consumers to exercise choice about behavioral tracking 

The information we collect automatically is statistical data and does not include personal information. This data helps us to improve our Services and to deliver better and more personalized features to you, including by enabling us to:

* Estimate our audience size and usage patterns. 
* Store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Services according to your individual interests. 
* Speed up your searches. 
* Recognize you when you return to our Services. 
* **Information We Collect From Other Sources**

We may also obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect through the Services. For example, we may collect information about you from third parties who provide services on our behalf, such as maintaining and monitoring usage of the Services and processing payment transactions. We also may receive information about you from the third parties with whom you interact through the Services.

**ANALYTICS SERVICES**

We may allow others to provide analytics service in connection with the Services, such as and Google Analytics. These entities may use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Services, including your IP address, web browser, pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked, and conversion information. We and others may use this information to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, personalize the user experience, and better understand your activity.

* To learn more about Google Analytics, please visit [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

**Children Under the Age of 13.**

Our Services are not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any personal information via our website. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not register on our website, make any purchases through our website, use any of the interactive or public comment features of our website or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com).

**How Do We Use Your Information?**

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information:

* To present our Services and its contents to you. The Company gathers user information to provide you with an effortless experience. For instance, your Personal Information enables us to greet you when you visit the Site and to provide you with specific information and services we think will be of interest to you. We review our users’ preferences, demographics, traffic patterns, and other information - as a whole - so that we can better understand who our audience is and what it wants. 
* To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us, including information about animals available for adoption or fostering. 
* To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide your information, such as connecting AWOs with pet lovers, reuniting you with your pets, connecting purchasers with sellers of Products, connecting you with veterinarians for telehealth purposes. 
* To verify your identity and, if applicable, authorization for you to use the Services.
* To prevent or address service, security, technical issues at your request in connection with customer support matters.
* To respond to your comments, questions, and requests.
* To provide you with notices about your Account. 
* To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection. 
* To create an individual or AWO profile and provide personalized services. 
* To notify you about changes to our Services or any products or services we offer or provide through it. 
* To allow you to participate in interactive features on our Services. 
* For the purpose of aggregated statistical analysis of how you and others use our website and our Services. 
* For targeted advertising. Targeted ads are probably more interesting to you and are more productive for our advertisers. Please note that we do not share your individual personal information with advertisers. We, or third-party ad servers acting on our behalf, act as the middleman between you and the advertisers that want to reach you. Our third-party ad servers may have access to your Personal Information but are bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy. Note, however, that we do not control the privacy policies of our advertisers and other third party sites to which we provide banner ads and links. A link to or embedded content from a third party website does not mean that we endorse that third party website, the quality or accuracy of information presented on the third party website or the persons or entities associated with the third party website. If you click-through a banner ad or link to and submit your information to an advertiser, you will be subject to their own privacy policies as applicable . We assume no responsibility or liability for these third party policies or the actions of non-affiliated third parties. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your information to others.
* To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide your information, such as connecting AWOs with pet lovers. 
* In any other way we may describe when you provide the information. 
* For any other purpose with your consent. 

We may also use your information to contact you about our own and third parties' goods and services that we believe may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to use your information in this way, please send us an email at [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com). For more information, see Choices About How We Use and Share Your Information below.

**How Is Your Information Shared?**

We may disclose aggregated information about users of our Site and/or our Services, and information that does not identify any individual, without restriction. This includes disclosing aggregated statistics to advertisers and other third parties. Note that aggregated information is not traceable to you specifically. 

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this Privacy Policy in the following ways: 

* To contractors, service providers and other third parties we use to support our business and who are bound by contractual obligations to keep Personal Information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them. 
* If you create an account with us or use our Services, we may share your name, postal address, email address, and shopping history with third-parties for their direct mail marketing purposes. If you would prefer that we not share information about you with third parties, please let us know by sending us an email stating your request to [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com).  
* To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution or other sale or transfer of some or all of Wagtopia's assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation or similar proceeding, in which Personal Information held by Wagtopia about our users is among the assets transferred. 
* To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it. In particular, when you provide us with your personal and organization information for purposes of connecting you with Wagtopia AWOs or pet lovers, or veterinarians for telehealth purposes, we will provide your information as you have requested. In addition, if you have registered a microchip on the microchip registry, we will share you and your pet’s relevant information (that you specifically provide for such use) with persons who enter the microchip number of your pet in the microchip lookup, enabling you to be reunited with lost pets. 
* We may use the information that is provided by you on Wagtopia forums, and any other User Contribution to the Site freely and without limitation. Please note that any information you post or disclose on the Site will become public information, and may be available to visitors to our website. We urge you to be very careful when deciding to disclose your Personal Information, or any other information, on the public areas of our website. 
* For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information. 
* To comply with any court order, law or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request. 
* To enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes. 
* If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of Wagtopia, our customers or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

Other than as described above, we will never provide your information to anyone for any purpose under any circumstances.

**What Are Your Choices About How We Use and Share Your Information?**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the information you provide to us. We have created mechanisms to give you the following controls over your information: 

**Tracking Technologies**. You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. For further information about how to do so, please refer to your browser “help” tool, or see www.allaboutcookies.org. Note that if you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of our website may be inaccessible or not function properly. You may also be able to opt out of mobile advertising identifiers and other non-cookie technologies. Note that, even if you opt out, these tracking technologies may still collect data and you will still see ads, but they will not be targeted based on the information collected from you. At this time, we do not respond to web browser “do not track” signals. If you would like to learn more about your ability to limit the information automatically shared with us and with third-party advertisers, visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt\_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

**Promotional Offers from Wagtopia**. If you do not wish to have your contact information used by Wagtopia to promote our own or third parties' products or services, you can opt-out by sending us an email stating your request to [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com).

If we have sent you a promotional email, the email will have an “unsubscribe” feature that will allow you to opt-out of receiving future email distributions.

**How Can You Access and Correct Your Information?**

You can always elect not to disclose information to us. However, please keep in mind that we may need some information to allow you to register with us, create an Account and/or to take advantage of some or all of our features, and if you choose not to provide that information, your ability to use our Services may be limited. 

You may send us an e-mail at [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com) to request access to, correct or delete any personal information that you have provided to us. You have the right to request what Personal Information we hold about you subject to our right to identity verification. If you request a copy of your data, we may charge you a fee, except where this is not permissible under applicable law. 

Whenever you have given us your consent to use your Personal Information, you have the right to change your mind at any time and withdraw that consent. 

In some jurisdictions, you have the right to correct or amend your Personal Information if it is inaccurate or needs to be updated. You may also have the right to request the deletion of your Personal Information, however this may not be always possible due to legal requirements and other obligations to keep such data. If we are asked to delete your data, we may keep some minimal information about you to be able to demonstrate that we have fulfilled our obligations.  In addition, we cannot delete all of your Personal Information except by also deleting your user Account. We may not accommodate a request to change information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect. 

If you delete your User Contributions from the Services, copies of your User Contributions may remain viewable in cached and archived pages, or might have been copied or stored by other Services users. Proper access and use of information provided on the Services, including User Contributions, is governed by our Terms of Use. 

**How Is Your Information Kept Secure?**

We work hard to protect your information and have implemented appropriate commercially reasonable physical, electronic and other security measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration and disclosure. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers behind firewalls and will be backed up on at least a weekly basis. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology.

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of the Services like the message boards or forums. The information you share in public areas may be viewed by any user of the Services.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to our Services. Any transmission of Personal Information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Services.  Therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you provide to us.  

**California privacy rights AND NOTICES**

**California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018, Cal. Civil Code § 1798.100 et seq., (“CCPA”)**

California law permits users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, a list of the third parties to whom we have disclosed their personal information (if any) for their direct marketing purposes in the prior calendar year, as well as the type of personal information disclosed to those parties. 

Wagtopia shall comply with the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018, Cal. Civil Code § 1798.100 et seq., (“CCPA”), which may be amended from time to time.  Per the terms of the CCPA, Wagtopia is a Service Provider and not a Third Party as described in the CCPA. Therefore, Wagtopia shall not:

* Sell the Personal Information.
* Retain, use, or disclose the Personal Information for any purpose other than providing the Services or for a Business Purpose. Specifically, Wagtopia shall not retain, use, or disclose the Personal Information for a Commercial Purpose.
* Retain, use, or disclose the Personal Information outside of the direct business relationship between Wagtopia and its users.

Notwithstanding anything in the Terms of Service or any related order form or other document, the parties acknowledge and agree that a user’s provision of Personal Information is not part of and explicitly excluded from the exchange of consideration, or any other thing of value, between the parties.

You have the right to request that we delete any Personal Information that we have collected from you. However, we are not required to comply with a request to delete, if it is necessary for us to retain the personal information in order to:

* Complete the transaction for which we collected the personal information, provide a product that you requested, take actions reasonably anticipated within the context of our ongoing business relationship with you, or otherwise perform our contract with you.
* Detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, or prosecute those responsible for such activities.
* Debug products to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality.
* Exercise free speech, ensure the right of another consumer to exercise their free speech rights, or exercise another right provided for by law.
* Comply with the California Electronic Communications Privacy Act (Cal. Penal Code § 1546 et. seq.).
* Engage in public or peer-reviewed scientific, historical, or statistical research in the public interest that adheres to all other applicable ethics and privacy laws, when the information’s deletion may likely render impossible or seriously impair the research’s achievement, if you previously provided informed consent.
* Enable solely internal uses that are reasonably aligned with consumer expectations based on your relationship with us.
* Comply with legal obligations.
* Make other internal and lawful uses of that information that are compatible with the context in which you provided it.

If you are a California resident and would like to request information or exercise your rights under the CCPA, please submit your request in an email to [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com). Only you, or a person or business entity registered with the California Secretary of State that you authorize to act on your behalf (an “authorized agent”), may make the requests set forth above. The request should include your contact information and describe your request with sufficient detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to it. In addition, you should provide sufficient information that allows us to reasonably verify that you are the person about whom we collected the personal information or an authorized representative of that person.   

We will respond to consumer requests in a reasonably timely manner. If we require extra time to respond, we will inform you of the reason and extension period in writing. In order to protect the security of your personal information, we will not honor a request if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm the personal information relates to you. The method used to verify your identity will depend on the type, sensitivity, and value of the information, including the risk of harm to you posed by any authorized access or deletion. Generally speaking, verification will be performed by matching the identifying information provided by you to the personal information that we already have. Any disclosures we provide will only cover the 12-month period preceding our receipt of your request (and will not be made more than twice in a 12-month period). If we cannot comply with a request, or cannot fully comply with a request, the response we provide will also explain the reasons we cannot comply.  

We do not sell your Personal Information or any information that may be used to identify you.

**RETENTION**

We will retain your Personal Information for the period of time that is necessary to fulfil the original purposes for which it has been collected. Please keep in mind that, in certain cases, a longer retention period may be required or permitted by law or to allow us to pursue our business interests, conduct audits, comply with our legal obligations, enforce our agreements or resolve any dispute. 

The criteria used to determine our retention periods include:

* Time needed to provide you with our Services or to operate our business.
* Whether your Account with us is active.  You may contact us to make your Account inactive at any time. 
* Legal, contractual, or similar obligations to retain your data, such as mandatory data retention laws in the applicable jurisdiction, government orders to preserve data relevant to an investigation, or data that must be retained for the purposes of contract or litigation. 

Please note that we are not responsible for storing any information that you provide to us or for any content or information that we provide to you. You are solely responsible for retaining backup files of any information and content that you provide or receive in connection with the Services.

**Transfer of Personal Information; International Visitors**

The Services are provided for access and use by persons located in the United States.  If you use the Services from outside of the United States, you do so at your own risk.  You are solely responsible for ensuring compliance with the laws of your specific jurisdiction, including the specific laws of your jurisdiction regarding the import, export, or re-export of the Services.  If you are outside the United States, you acknowledge that by providing your Personal Information, you are: (a) permitting the transfer of your Personal Information to the United States which may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you reside; and (b) permitting the use of your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy and applicable law. 

* **Filing a complaint:** In some jurisdictions, including according to data protection laws in the EU for complaints issued from subjects in the EU, you have the right to lodge a formal complaint with a data protection authority.

**OPTIONS**

**Your Information**  

We use reasonable processes to ensure compliance with this privacy policy and periodically verify that the policy is accurate. We encourage you to raise any concerns by contacting us at [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com), and we will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of information. Unless legal restrictions apply, you have the right to access the information we hold about you free of charge. You may update, correct or delete your information at any time by contacting us at [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com). You can help us maintain the accuracy of your information by notifying us of any changes. To avoid delays in obtaining your information, please provide sufficient detail to permit us to identify you and the specific information that you are requesting. We will respond to your request within 30 days of receipt, unless we inform you that it will take longer, as permitted by law under certain circumstances. Please note that there may be instances where access may be restricted as permitted or required by law. We will advise you of the reasons for restricting access subject to any legal or regulatory limitations. In addition, please note that we may retain certain information as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. We may also retain cached or archived copies of information about you for a certain period. Please note that we are not responsible for storing any information that you provide to us or a third party or for any content or information that we or a third party provide to you. You are solely responsible for retaining backup files of any information and content that you provide or receive in connection with the Services.

**Marketing Communications**

You may opt out of receiving marketing communications from us by following the instructions in those communications or by emailing us at [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com). In such cases, we will retain minimum Personal Information to note that you opted out in order to avoid contacting you again.  

Please note that even if you opt out from receiving marketing communications, we may still send you administrative communications, such as technical updates for our Services, order confirmations, notifications about your Account activities, and other important notices.

**Non-Discrimination**

We will not discriminate against you because you elect to exercise any of the rights related to your Personal Information, including but not limited to:

* Denying you products or Services;
* Charging you different prices or rates for Services, including through the use of discounts or other benefits or imposing penalties on you;
* Providing a different level or quality of Services to you; or
* Suggesting that you will receive a different price or rate for Services or a different level or quality of Services.

**What If There Are Changes to Our Privacy Policy?**

We post any changes we make to our Privacy Policy on this page. If we make material changes to how we treat your personal information, we will notify you by e-mail to the e-mail address specified in your account, if you have one. We will not use your Personal Information in a way that is materially different than the uses described in this Policy without giving you an opportunity to opt out of such differing uses. Your continued use of the Services after this Policy has been amended shall be deemed to be your continued acceptance of the terms and conditions of the Policy, as amended. The date the Privacy Policy was last updated is identified at the bottom of this page. You are responsible for ensuring we have an up-to-date, active and deliverable e-mail address for you and for periodically visiting our Services and this Privacy Policy to check for any changes.

**What If You Have Questions or Comments?**

To ask questions or comment about this Privacy Policy and our privacy practices, you may contact us at [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com).    

**STATE ADDENDUM TO THE WAGTOPIA PRIVACY**

**Addendum Date****: March 14, 2023**

This State Addendum to the Wagtopia Privacy Policy (“Addendum”) supplements the terms of Wagtopia’s Privacy Policy and applies to individuals who are residents of California, Colorado, Connecticut, Virginia, and Utah, as specified below.  It describes the rights you may have, depending on the state of your residence, with regard to your personal information, which apply when new or updated laws take effect in these states. This Addendum does not apply to any employees, owners, directors, officers, or contractors of Wagtopia or its affiliates.

**I. California Privacy Policy**

The section relates solely to residents of the State of California, and for purposes of this section, "you" means residents of the State of California. This section will provide you with information about our information practices and your privacy rights under the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA), the California Privacy Rights Act (CPRA) and applicable regulations (collectively referred to as "CPRA"). Any terms defined in the CPRA have the same meaning when used in this section.

**1) Personal Information we collect**

Wagtopia collects information that identifies, relates to, describes, references, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular California consumer or household ("CPRA Covered Personal Information" or "personal information"). CPRA Covered Personal Information does not include personal information that has been de-identified or aggregated, or that is publicly available information from government records.

In particular, we have collected the following categories of CPRA Covered Personal Information from consumers (as that term is defined in the CPRA) within the last twelve (12) months:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Category | Examples | Collected |
| A. Personal Identifiers. | A real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, Account name, Social Security number, driver's license number, passport number, or other similar identifiers. | Yes |
| B. Personal and financial information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)). | A name, signature, Social Security number, physical characteristics or description, address, telephone number, passport number, driver's license or state identification card number, insurance policy number, education, employment, employment history, bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, medical information, or health insurance information. Some personal information included in this category may overlap with other categories. | Yes |
| C. Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law. | Age (40 years or older), race, national origin, citizenship, religion or creed, marital status, medical condition, physical or mental disability, sex (including gender, gender identity, gender expression, pregnancy or childbirth and related medical conditions), sexual orientation, veteran or military status. | No  |
| D. Commercial information. | Records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies. | Yes |
| E. Biometric information. | Genetic, physiological, behavioral, and biological characteristics, or activity patterns used to extract a template or other identifier or identifying information, such as, fingerprints, faceprints, and voiceprints, iris or retina scans, keystroke, gait, or other physical patterns, and sleep, health, or exercise data. | No  |
| F. Internet or other similar network activity. | Browsing history, search history, information on your interaction with a Site, application, or advertisement. | Yes |
| G. Geolocation data. | Physical location or movements. | No  |
| H. Sensory data. | Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information. | No  |
| I. Professional or employment related information | Occupation, title, employer information, current or past job history or performance evaluations. | No  |
| J. Non-public education information (per the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. Section 1232g, 34 C.F.R. Part 99)). | Education records directly related to a student maintained by an educational institution or party acting on its behalf, such as grades, transcripts, class lists, student schedules, student identification codes, student financial information, or student disciplinary records. | No  |
| J. Inferences drawn from other personal information. | Profile reflecting a person's preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes. | No  |
| L. Sensitive Personal Information | Social security, driver's license, state identification or passport numbers; Account log-in, financial account, debit or credit card number in combination with any required security or access code, password or credentials allowing access to an Account; precise geolocation data; racial or ethnic origin, religious or philosophical beliefs or union membership, content of mail, email and text messages unless business is the intended recipient; genetic data; processing of biometric information for the purposes of uniquely identifying a consumer; personal information collected and analyzed concerning your health. | Yes |

 **2) Categories of sources from which we collect personal information**

You have the right to know the categories of sources from which we collect your personal information. We make this information available to you in the WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT section of our Privacy Policy.

 **3) Our processing of your personal information**

You have the right to know how we process and use your personal information. We make this information available to you in the HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION  section of our Privacy Policy.

 **4) Disclosure of Personal Information**

You have the right to know if we share your personal information with any third parties and the categories of those third parties. We make this information available to you in the HOW IS YOUR INFORMATION SHARED section of our Privacy Notice.

 **5) No Sales or Sharing of Personal Information**

We do not sell personal information for monetary or other consideration, and we do not share your personal information for cross-context behavioral advertising (as defined in the CPRA). We have also not sold or shared the personal information of consumers under 16 years of age.

**6) Use of Sensitive Personal Information**

We do not use or disclose sensitive personal information for purposes other than those specified in section 7027, subsection (m) of the CPRA regulations and we do not collect or process sensitive personal information for purposes of inferring characteristics about you.

 **7) Your CPRA Consumer Rights**

1. Where we are acting as a business (as opposed to a service provider as those terms are defined in the CPRA), you have the following rights:
    * **Right to Access.**  You have the right to request that we disclose the categories of personal information we collected about you, the categories of sources for the personal information we collected about you, our business or commercial purpose for collecting your personal information, the categories of third parties with whom we share your personal information; and the specific pieces of personal information we collected about you.
    * **Right to data portability.**   You have the right to obtain a copy of your data in a portable, and to the extent technically feasible, readily usable format that allows you to transmit the data to a third party.
    * **Right to delete.**  You may have the right to request that we delete your personal information where we act as a business. This right is subject to several exceptions and we may deny your deletion request if retaining the information is necessary for us or our service providers to:
        * Complete the transaction for which we collected the personal information and take actions reasonably anticipated within the context of our ongoing business relationship with you or our client;
        * Detect bugs or errors in our Services, detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, or prosecute those responsible for such activities;
        * Enable solely internal uses that are reasonably aligned with consumer expectations based on your relationship with us;
        * Comply with a legal obligation; or
        * Make other internal and lawful uses of that information as permitted by law or that are compatible with the context in which we collected it.
    * **Right to correct.**  We take reasonable steps to ensure that information we hold about you is accurate and complete. However, you have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate personal information that we have about you.
    * **Right to non-discrimination and no retaliation.**  We will not discriminate or retaliate against you for exercising any of your rights under the CCPA, including we will not deny you goods or services, charge you different prices for goods or services, provide you a different level or quality of goods or services, or suggest that you will receive a different price for goods or services or a different level of quality of goods and services.
2. Exercising Your Rights
    
    You may exercise your rights to know, delete and correct as described above by submitting a verifiable request to us by emailing us at [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com). 
    
3. Verification Process
    
    We are only required to fulfill verifiable requests. Only you, you as a parent or a legal guardian on behalf of a minor child, or your authorized agent may make a verifiable request related to personal information.   If you submit your request through an authorized agent, we may require you to provide your agent with written permission to do so and verify your identity. We may deny any request by an authorized agent that does not submit proof that the agent has been authorized by you to act on your behalf.
    
    * **For requests for access to categories of personal information,** we will verify your request to a "reasonable degree of certainty." This may include matching at least two data points that you would need to provide with data points we maintain about you and that we have determined to be reliable for the purposes of
    * **For requests for specific pieces of personal information (portability request),** we will verify your request to a "reasonably high degree of certainty." This may include matching at least three data points that you would need to provide with the data points we maintain about you and that we have determined to be reliable for the purposes of verification. We will also require you to submit a signed declaration under penalty of perjury that you are the consumer whose personal information is the subject of the request.
    * **For requests to delete,** we will verify your request to a "reasonable degree" or a "reasonably high degree of certainty" depending on the sensitivity of the personal information and the risk of harm to the consumer posed by unauthorized deletion.
    
    We will use the personal information you provide in a request only for purposes of verifying your identity or authority to make the request.
    
4.  Response Timing and Format
    
    We will respond to a verifiable request within forty-five (45) days of its receipt, and will notify you within those forty-five (45) days if we require more time to respond and the reasons for the additional time.  If you have an Account with us, we will deliver our written response to that Account. If you do not have an Account with us, we will deliver our written response by mail or electronically, at your option.  (Note that the law prohibits us from disclosing at any time a consumer's Social Security number, driver's license number or other government-issued identification number, financial account number, any health insurance or medical identification number, an Account password, security questions and answers, or any unique biometric data.)  If we cannot comply with a request or a portion of the request, we will include the reasons in our response. If we deny your request on the basis that it is impossible or would involve a disproportionate effort, we will explain our reasons, such as the data is not in a searchable or readily accessible format, is maintained for only legal or compliance purposes, or is not sold or used for any commercial purpose and our inability to disclose it, delete or correct it would not impact you in any material manner.
    
    We do not charge a fee to process or respond to your verifiable request unless it is excessive, repetitive, or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that the request warrants a fee, we will tell you why we made that decision and provide you with a cost estimate before completing your request.
    
    \*Please note that in certain cases we may collect your personal information as a service provider (as opposed to a business, as those terms are defined in the CPRA) pursuant to a contract we have with a commercial client (the CPRA business) to provide a service. In such a case, we are required to collect and process your information only based on the instructions received from the business. Should you direct your requests to exercise your rights to us, we may be required to share your request with the business, who is the party responsible under the CPRA for receiving, verifying and responding to your requests, or we may direct you to make your request directly to the business.

 **8) CPRA exemptions**

This section (California Privacy Policy) does not apply to the following data which is exempt from the CPRA, including but not limited to: medical information governed by the California Confidentiality of Medical Information Act (CMIA); protected health information collected by a covered entity or business associate governed by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA), or personal information collected, processed, sold, or disclosed pursuant to certain sector-specific privacy laws, including the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA), the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA) or California Financial Information Privacy Act (FIPA), and the Driver's Privacy Protection Act of 1994 (DPPA).

 **9) Other California Privacy Rights**

California's "Shine the Light" law (Civil Code Section § 1798.83) permits users of our Services who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to affiliates and other third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com).

**II. Notice of Colorado, Connecticut, Virginia and Utah Privacy Rights**

The section relates solely to residents of the States of Colorado, Connecticut, Virginia and Utah, and provides you with information about your privacy rights under the Colorado Privacy Act (CPA), the Connecticut Data Privacy Act (CDPA), the Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act (VCDPA) and the Utah Consumer Privacy Act (UCPA).

This section shall be effective for the residents of those States on the dates set forth below:

* Effective January 1, 2023, for residents of the State of Virginia
* Effective July 1, 2023, for residents of the States of Colorado and Connecticut
* Effective December 31, 2023, for residents of the State of Utah

For purposes of this section, "residents", "consumers" or "you" means individuals of those states who are acting in their individual or household context. This section does not apply to individuals acting in their commercial or employment context.

1.  **Personal Information we collect**
    
    You have a right to know the categories and types of personal information we collect about you. We make this information available to you in the WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT section of our Privacy Policy.
    
2. **Categories of sources from which we collect personal information**
    
    You have the right to know the categories of sources from which we collect your personal information. We make this information available to you in the WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT section of our Privacy Policy.
    
3. **Our processing of your personal information**
    
    You have the right to know how we process and use your personal information. We make this information available to you in the HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION section of our Privacy Policy.
    
    \*For residents of the State of Virginia, to the extent that we maintain de-identified data, we take reasonable measures to ensure that de-identified data cannot be associated with a natural person, we publicly commit to maintaining and using de-identified data without attempting to re-identify the data, and we contractually obligate any recipient of the data to comply with the same obligations.
    
4.  **Disclosure of Personal Information**
    
    You have the right to know if we share your personal information with any third parties. We make this information available to you in the HOW IS YOUR INFORMATION SHARED section of our Privacy Policy.
    
5.  **No Sale of Data or Use of Data for Targeted Advertising**
    
    We do not currently sell your personal information and we do not currently use your data for targeted advertising (as that term is defined by your applicable state law). We may send you advertising in response to your request for information or feedback or based on your activities with our Services, including your search queries and visits to our Services. However, we will not send you targeted advertising based on your activities across non-affiliated websites, applications or platforms to predict your preferences or interests.
    
6.  **Your Rights**
    1. Where we act as the Controller of your personal information (as opposed to a Processor as those terms are defined in your applicable State law), you have the right to submit a request to us for the following:
        * **Right to access.**  You have the right to know if we process your personal information and have access to such information and certain details of how we use it.
        * **Right to correct.**  We take reasonable steps to ensure that information we hold about you is accurate and complete. However, you have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate personal information that we have about you.
        * **Right to delete.**  You may have the right to request that we delete your personal information where we act as a controller. This right is subject to several exceptions and we may deny your deletion request if retaining the information is necessary for us or our processors to:
            * Complete the transaction for which we collected the personal information and take actions reasonably anticipated within the context of our ongoing business relationship with you or our client;
            * Detect bugs or errors in our Services, detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, or prosecute those responsible for such activities;
            * Enable solely internal uses that are reasonably aligned with consumer expectations based on your relationship with us;
            * Comply with a legal obligation; or
            * Make other internal and lawful uses of that information as permitted by law or that are compatible with the context in which we collected it.
        * **Right to restriction of processing (opt-out).**  You have the right to opt-out of processing your personal information for purposes of profiling in furtherance of any automated processing of your data that produce legal or similarly significant effects concerning you. (This right only applies to residents of the States of Colorado, Connecticut and Virginia.)
        * **Right to data portability.**  You have the right to obtain a copy of your data in a portable, and to the extent technically feasible, readily usable format that allows you to transmit the data to a third party.
        * **Right to non-discrimination and no retaliation.**  We will not discriminate or retaliate against you for exercising any of your rights, including but not limited to, by denying you goods or services, charging you different prices for goods or services, or providing you a different level or quality of goods or services.
        * **Right to restrict the processing of sensitive information** Unless we are processing your sensitive information pursuant to any of the legal exemptions listed in Section 8 (Exemptions) below or as otherwise allowed by law:
            * For residents of the States of Connecticut, Virginia and Colorado, we will not process your sensitive information without first obtaining your consent; and
            * For residents of the State of Utah, we will not process your sensitive personal information without providing you with notice and an opportunity to opt out.
    2. Exercising Your Rights
        
        You may exercise your rights to know, delete and correct as described above by submitting a verifiable request to us by emailing us at [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com).
        
    3. Authentication Process
        
        We will only fulfill request when we can verify your identify and confirm that you are authority to make such a request. Only you, you as the parent or legal guardian on behalf of your minor child, or your authorized agent, guardian or conservator may make a request related to personal information. If an authorized agent, legal guardian or conservator submits the request, we may require your written permission to do so and may require additional information to authenticate your identity. We may deny a request by an authorized agent, legal guardian or conservator who does not submit proof of authorization to act on your behalf.  We will only use the personal information you provide in a request to verify your identity or authority to make the request.
        
    4. Response Timing and Format
        
        We will respond to an authenticated request within forty- five (45) days of its receipt, and will notify you within those forty-five (45) days if we require more time to respond and the reasons for the additional time.  If you have an Account with us, we will deliver our written response to that Account. If you do not have an Account with us, we will deliver our written response by mail or electronically, at your option.  If we cannot comply with a request or a portion of the request, we will include the reasons in our response.
        
        \*For residents of the States of Colorado, Connecticut and Utah, you may make one request within a twelve-month period at no charge. 
        
        \*For residents of the State of Virginia, you may make a request up to two (2) times within a twelve (12) month period at no charge. We reserve the right to charge a fee to process or respond to any request that we consider excessive, repetitive, or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that the request warrants a fee, we will tell you why we made that decision and provide you with a cost estimate before completing your request.
        
7. **Right to Appeal**
    
    You have the right to appeal our decision within a reasonable period of time after receipt of our response. You may appeal our decision by sending us an email at [support@petstablished.com](mailto:support@petstablished.com). We will respond to your appeal within 60 days of receipt (45 days of receipt for residents of Colorado) and will inform you of any decisions and the reasons for such decisions.
    
    \* Please note that in certain cases we may collect your personal information as a processor (as opposed to a controller, as those terms are defined in your applicable state privacy law) pursuant to a contract we have with a commercial client (the controller) to provide a service. In such a case, we are required to collect and process your information only based on the instructions received from the controller. Should you direct your requests to exercise your rights to us, we may be required to share your request with the controller, who is the party responsible under your applicable state privacy law for receiving, authenticating and responding to your requests.
    
8. **Exemptions**
    
    This section (Notice of Colorado, Connecticut, Virginia and Utah Privacy Rights) does not apply to certain entities and data that are exempt from your applicable state privacy law, including but not limited to the following: covered entities, business associates and protected health information governed by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) and the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act (HITECH); financial institutions and personal information subject to the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA); and personal information collected, processed, sold, or disclosed pursuant to certain sector-specific privacy laws, including the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA), the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act, the Farm Credit Act and the Driver's Privacy Protection Act of 1994 (DPPA).

Be the first to know about new  
features and promotions
========================================================

Subscribe

About Us
========

Resources
=========

Contact
=======

© 2024 Petstablished. All Rights Reserved. v1.0
